

Objective:

Enthusiastic software professional having more than 19 Years of experience in Architecting, designing, development and integration of highly scalable enterprise applications using Java, AWS and MuleSoft Technologies with deep domain knowledge in financial services and healthcare services. Looking forward to work in a challenging environment, where there is an opportunity to learn new technologies and apply my skills effectively towards the growth of organization.

Career Expertise:

- ✓ More than 19 Years of IT experience with expertise in Financial Services and Healthcare domain with respect to requirements gathering, architecture, design, development, implementation, and end user support as well as team management.
- ✓ About 1 year of onshore experience (Australia) in the implementation and Operational Risk Management Application and in coordination of the offshore team in enhancing the application with new functionalities.
- ✓ Extensive **AWS** and **MuleSoft** experience in design, development and implementation of multi-tenant Service oriented architecture using Anypoint Platform and managing the API using MuleSoft.
- ✓ Have implemented API led connectivity approach as part of modernization of legacy applications for one the leading health care regulatory agency in the United Kingdom.
- ✓ Have worked for a HR system transformation for a leading UK client from scratch using Mule 4.
- ✓ Skilled in designing integration systems with in-depth knowledge of Enterprise Integration Patterns.
- ✓ Well versed with XML, JSON transformations, exposing and consuming SOAP based and **RESTful** web services for integration using MuleSoft.
- ✓ Have worked on MuleSoft integration with systems like SAP, Oracle DB, Oracle Fusion, Documentum, SAP SuccessFactors, Workday, Salesforce etc.,
- ✓ Expertise in development of web-based applications with good programming skills in Core Java, Servlets and Spring Framework.
- ✓ Good understanding of MVC Architecture, Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) methodologies, conversant with Unified Modeling Language (UML), and Object-Oriented Analysis and Design (OOAD)
- ✓ Experience in RDBMS like DB2 and Oracle (SQL & PLSQL) and ORM like **Hibernate**
- ✓ Have been part of multiple agile projects and well versed with **Agile methodologies** and **DevOps.**
- ✓ Result oriented professional with a view of taking professional approach to problems and provide efficient solutions.
- ✓ Exhibited Technical leadership by collaborating with Product Owners, Enterprise Data Architects, Quality Assurance, Business Operations and Project Management Teams.

Educational Qualifications:

> Post-Graduation

Master of Computer Applications, Bharathidasan University

> Graduation

BSc Statistics, Bharathidasan University

Employment History:

Accenture Solutions India Pvt Limited, Bangalore

Designation: Technology Architect - Associate Manager.

Duration: June 2016 – Till Date

Wipro Technologies, Bangalore

Designation : Technical Architect. **Duration** : April 2014 – June 2016

IBM India Software Labs Pvt Ltd, Bangalore

Designation : Advisory Software Engineer.Duration : November 2004 – March 2014

Atos Origin India Pvt Ltd, Mumbai

Designation : Software Engineer.

Duration: March 2004 – October 2004

Harjai Computers Pvt Ltd, Mumbai

Designation: Software Engineer.

Duration: September 2003 – February 2004

Projects Description:

Project Title : Retailer Evolution Master Data
Client : Leading Tobacco company in UK

Technologies : AWS Lamba using Python, API Gateway, S3, Event Bridge, Cognito, Step Functions, DynamoDB, Secrets Manager, Relational Database Service RDS, Database Migration Service DMS,

Kinesis Data Stream, Change Data Capture CDC and Terraform for IaC.

Duration : Nov 2022 – Till Date

Brief description: Setting up a master data for customer data including account and contact for the business. Critical information comes from multiple sources and this master data platform create a single version of truth and provides 360 degrees of the consumer insights.

Project Title: Digital Transformation

Client : Leading Insurance Company in US

Technologies : MuleSoft 4.3, RAML, REST API, SOAP, DB2

Duration : Feb 2020 – Till Date

Brief description: This project is about the modernization of existing platform using OutSystems and MuleSoft APIs for integration. As part of integration with the back-end systems MuleSoft API led, architecture is followed.

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Work closely with Enterprise architect to understand the logical business process and design the API as required for the implementation.
- Interact with API consumers to demonstrate the API capabilities and receive feedback for improving the user experience.

- Build common reusable components required for implementation of Customers, Products, Recipes
- Participate in sprint planning meeting with product owners, scrum master and review the product backlog and plan the deliverables for each sprint.
- Support the quality team for any issues raised in the API's develop, review the gap with business leads and provide fixes if required.
- Publishing performance test metrics to business stakeholders for minimum load, peak load, and average load conditions.
- Create automated scripts for CI/CD process and promote the application to higher environments
- Provide training to business users about the latest releases, capabilities and efficiently use the features exposed by the API's

Project Title: Clinical Trials - Application Modernization

Client : Medicines and Healthcare Products Regulatory Agency (MHRA)

Technologies : Java, Microservices, MuleSoft 4.2, CloudHub Platform, RAML, REST, JSON, XML

Duration : March 2017 – Dec 2019

Brief description: Clinical Trials Transformation is first project in line with client decision to modernize existing regulatory application estate and re-platform to digital technologies, which will help the Agency to prepare for changing business requirements. As part of this project, the existing legacy application will be re-build using Microservices, MuleSoft and Appian technologies.

Roles and responsibilities:

- ✓ Designing solution for application modernization and transformations in line with clients digital Strategies.
- ✓ Implementation of modern digital transformations with legacy systems by defining new System API, Process API and Experience API using MuleSoft API led connectivity approach
- ✓ Comprehensively used MuleSoft's CloudHub and its products like API Analytics, API Manager, Runtime manager and Insights for delivering project
- ✓ Lead application development by providing technical guidance on MuleSoft to other developers and functional knowledge to testers for successful delivery
- ✓ Work closely with the quality team in testing and reviewing any requirement gaps with the business analyst and address them

Project Title: ICSR R3 - R2 Conversion

Client : Medicines and Healthcare Products Regulatory Agency (MHRA)

Technologies : Java, MuleSoft 3.8.5, CloudHub Platform, RAML, REST, OAuth, JSON, XML

Duration : July 2016 – January 2017

Brief description: Within the context of medicines, Marketing Authorization Holders submit reports of adverse reactions associated with medicinal products to the MHRA. The reports are known as Individual Case Safety Reports- ICSR. Earlier these reports were in R2 xml format. From November 2017 it was required to receive ICSRs in the new ICH E2B R3 format. This Project is to convert the R3 format to R2 Format and provide seamless integration with legacy systems

Roles and responsibilities:

- ✓ Design high-level solution for ICSR R2 t R3 transformations in line with clients digital Strategies.
- ✓ Implementation of proposed solution by defining new System API, Process API and Experience API with from systems like Documentum, Oracle.

- ✓ Responsible for setup of the VPN setup between CloudHub VPC and MHRA on premise systems.
- ✓ Comprehensively used MuleSoft's CloudHub and its products like API Analytics, Runtime manager and Insights for delivering project
- ✓ Lead application development by providing technical guidance on MuleSoft to other developers and functional knowledge to testers for successful delivery
- ✓ Mentored and trained team members in MuleSoft for leveraging the functional capabilities of existing team members for building new applications

Project Title: Enterprise Server Upgrade

Client : ANZ Bank

Technologies : Java, OpenPages GRC Platform

Duration : May 2014 – June 2016

Project Title : IBM OpenPages GRC Platform

: IBM Master Data Management

: IBM Mashup Center

: Portal Integration for WebSphere Product Center

Client : IBM

Technologies : Java, EJB, WebSphere Duration : Nov 2004 – Mar 2014

Project Title: Pampers Portal

Client : P&G

Technologies : Java, JavaScript, HTML, ATG

Duration : Sep 2003 – Oct 2004

Certifications:

- ✓ AWS Certified Solution Architect Associate
- ✓ AWS Certified Machine Learning Specialty
- ✓ AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner
- ✓ MuleSoft Certified Platform Architect
- ✓ MuleSoft Certified Integration Architect
- ✓ MuleSoft Certified Developer (Mule 4)
- ✓ IBM Certified Developer InfoSphere MDM Server
- ✓ Sun Certified Java Programmer
- ✓ Accenture Certified Associate Technical Architect

Personal Details:

Email: toskumar@yahoo.com

Mobile: 9900457611